OBAIDUR RAHMAN | OBIE

Full Stack Web Developer | Microsoft Dynamics 365 Developer | Browser Extension Developer

J +880 1686 333 153

Mirpur, Dhaka, Bangladesh

theobaidur.github.io



With 11+ years of experience in Web Design and Development. I have got extensive experience in full stack web development, Microsoft Dynamics 365, Browser Extension Development and others. I am passionate with JavaScript, Typescript, React, Angular, NodeJs, PHP, etc. and of course, Open Source.

I always look for a challenging position in a dynamic environment where I can utilize my skills and knowledge to the fullest extent for the growth of the organization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

Concourse Federal Group, USA | June 2018 - Present

At Concourse Federal Group, I am working as a Full Stack Web Developer. Its the most diversified team I have ever worked with. So far, I have worked with React, Angular, NodeJs, Microsoft Dynamics 365, Azure, etc.

My responsibility at concourse were mainly,

- Building custom web applications for the company and its clients.
- Ensuring the quality of the code and the applications built.
- Leading the team and mentoring the new team members.

Sr. Front End Developer

CALL & SOLUTION, Bangladesh | Oct 2017 - May 2018

At Call & Solution, I was working as a Sr. Front End Developer. I mainly worked with AngularJs & Angular here. My responsibility at Call & Solution were,

- Updating the existing web applications and maintaining them.
- Migrating the existing web applications to Angular 2+ from AngularJs.

Sr. Front End Developer

Diva Worldwide, Bangladesh / Netherlands | March 2017 - Sept 2017

Diva worldwide was probably the 2nd best company I have ever worked. I loved the nature of work and the people I worked with. I was the team lead of the front end team.

My responsibility at Diva worldwide,

- Design and develop of the world class Rich Media Ads for different multinational companies.
- Ensuring the quality of the code and the products
- Mentoring the new team members.

Full Stack Developer

Lineup Lab, USA | Sept 2014 - February 2016

At Lineup Lab, I started my career as a front end developer. I was the first employee of the company. I was responsible for the development of the company's first product, Lineup Lab. I was there from paper sketch to the first release of the fully functional product.

My responsibility at Lineup lab,

- Designing and developing the front end of the Lineup Lab using AngularJs.
- Developing the back end of the Lineup Lab using PHP, Slim Framework.
- Establishing best practices for the development of the Lineup Lab.

SKILLS

Languages

JavaScript (ES6+), TypeScript, PHP, SQL, HTML, CSS, Python, C#

- Mostly comfortable with JavaScript, TypeScript and PHP.
- Worked with Python and C# as well.
- Worked with SQL and NoSQL databases.
- Working with HTML and CSS for more than 10 years.

Full Stack Web Development

React, Angular, VueJs, NodeJs, ExpressJs, Laravel, Django, ASP.NET MVC, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Firebase,

- For frontend development, I mostly use React, Angular and Vue.js.
- For backend development, I mostly use Node.js and Laravel.
- For SQL databases, I mostly use MySQL. And for NoSQL databases, I mostly use Firebase.

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Science

2019 - 2020

Jahangirnagar University

- Savar, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Bachelor of Computer Science and Engineering

2012 - 2016

University of Asia Pacific

- Dhaka, Bangladesh

LANGUAGES

Bangla

Native

Speaking, Reading, Writing, Listening

English

Speaking, Reading, Writing, Listening

FIND ME AT

Github

github.com/theobaidur

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/theobaidur

Stack Overflow

linkedin.com/in/theobaidur

NPM

npmjs.com/~theobaidur

Microsoft Dynamics 365

Microsoft Dynamics 365, Share Point, Power Apps, Power BI, Power Automate, Model Driven Apps, Microsoft Teams,

- 3+ years of experience in Microsoft Dynamics 365
- Developed custom applications for popular Microsoft products like SharePoint, Teams, etc
- Developed custom control for Microsoft Power Platform using PowerApps Component Framework.
- Got Hands-on experience on Microsoft Power Automate, Power Bi, etc.

Browser Extension Development

Chrome Extension, Firefox Extension, Edge Extension,

- 5+ years of experience in browser extension development.
- Developed extensions for in house use and for the public.
- Published extensions on Chrome Web Store, Firefox Add-ons and Microsoft Edge Add-ons.

Cloud Technologies

Azure, AWS, Digital Ocean,

- 2+ years of experience in cloud technologies.
- Deployed applications on Azure, AWS and Digital Ocean.
- Developed and deployed serverless applications using Azure Functions, Aws Lambda
- Developed custom storage solutions using Azure Blob Storage, AWS S3, Digital Ocean Spaces.

App Development

HyBrid Mobile App, Desktop App, Progressive Web App,

- Hands on experience in developing hybrid mobile apps using Ionic, Angular, ReactNative, etc.
- Developed desktop apps using Electron and other web technologies.
- Developed Progressive Web Apps using React, Angular, Vue, etc.

Others

Git, GitHub, BitBucket,CI/CD,Figma,Adobe Photoshop,

- I use Git for version control and GitHub, BitBucket, Azure DevOps for code hosting.
- I use Figma for designing and Adobe Photoshop for editing images.
- Have experience in setting up CI/CD pipelines using Azure DevOps, Github Actions, etc.